MICHAEL BRIAN WARD

FRONT-END DEVELOPER REACT/JS

PROFILE

I have a very mixed background when it comes to my job experience, but every job I had I received promotions and ended up taking on a leadership role. I have always taken pride in my work, and for the first time in my life I feel I am where I belong with coding.

CONTACT EMAIL

thewardbunch@gmail.com

PORTFOLIO

https://bwardstories.github.io/portfolio/

LINKEDIN

https://tinyurl.com/w3tp4naw

PHONE/CITY/STATE

(843) 214-3314

Bonneau, SC 29431

LANGUAGES, OTHER SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Express, Zustand, Bootstrap, MongoDB, APIs, Git, Data Structures, Deployment, RESTful APIs,

EXPERIENCE

LEAD ELECTRICIAN, ELITE ELECTRIC CO., SUMMERVILLE, SC

JAN 2017-MAR 2020

Purchased materials for jobs, supervised training of new hires, assigned tasks for workers, kept track of total man hours up to 8 workers per job, made sure all work passed inspections. 100% passed inspections rate for term of employment

PAWN SHOP MANAGER, MONEY MAN PAWN, SUMMERVILLE, SC

APRIL 2012- NOV 2016

Oversaw training for new hires, managed annual payroll budget of over \$500,000 for 11 employees, researching items and qualifying loans on said items.

STORE MANAGER, DOLLAR GENERAL, CROSS, SC

MAY 2009- APRIL 2012

Managed annual payroll budget of \$300,000 for up to 10 employees, purchasing merchandise to keep store stocked, training new hires

STORE MANAGER, MONEY MAN PAWN, SUMMERVILLE, SC

NOV 2006- MAY 2009

Responsible for training new hires, managing payroll budget, researching items and qualifying loans on said items.

LEAD ELECTRICIAN, ELITE ELECTRIC CO., SUMMERVILLE, SC

APRIL 1999 - NOV 2006

Purchased materials for jobs, supervised training of new hires, assigned tasks for workers, kept track of total man hours for job.

EDUCATION

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPEMENT

KENZIE ACADEMY, INDIANAPOLIS IN APRIL 2021